marcelrominger

portfolio

rominger.net be.net/romingermarcel

contact

Uhlandstr. 48 73770 Denkendorf Germany

+49 157 32083447 rominger.marcel@gmail.com

personal

10/27/1988 Male German

languages

German native English fluent Swedish beginner French beginner

education

2014-2015

M.Sc. Human-Computer Interaction and Social Media Umeå universitet, Sweden My thesis was about the combination of eye-tracking and speech recognition in order to control a computer system. The idea draws upon embodied interaction in order to allow for a more natural interaction.

2008-2012 **B.Sc.** Computer Science

Hochschule für Technik Stuttgart, Germany My thesis was about an innovative real-time based residential power scheduling scheme for smart grids. The implementation was done in Java.

experience

2013-2014 **Verivox GmbH**

Software systems engineer

As part of a multicultural scrum team, I helped to maintain and improve Germany's best and most popular comparison website of the years 2012, 2013 and 2014. We worked closely together with the UX team. Together we attended sprint kickoffs, daily scrum meetings, retrospectives, general project planning or were supporting each other in daily business tasks. We developed using C#, ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript(jQuery), HTML, CSS, Visual Studio and Subversion. We applied techniques like test-driven development, MVC, inversion of control, dependency injection, unobtrusive JavaScript, REST and AJAX.

2012-2013 **Thales Deutschland GmbH**

Software engineer

One part of my work was to improve an already existing internal software tool. The work involved VBA, XML as well as Subversion. Contextual inquiry was applied in order to improve the user experience and user interface. I describe my role as in-house support for the users as well as maintenance and improvement of the software tool.

The other part of my work involved working in a scrum team. We developed a completely new internal tool using C#, AutoCAD .NET, WPF, MVVM, Visual Studio and Subversion. The work involved creating the user interface, specifying the system architecture as well as implementing and testing.

2011-2012 **Bombardier Transportation GmbH**

Mannheim, Germany

Böblingen, Germany

Heidelberg, Germany

Stuttgart, Germany

Working student - System architecture

My work involved assisting a system architect in daily business tasks. I created UML diagrams with Enterprise Architect and was administrating a Linux server as well as a MySQL database.

IBM Deutschland Research & Development GmbH 2010-2011

Intern - Quality assurance

I was part of an international team. I developed and validated functional and regression tests for IBM DB2 and IBM DB2 Optim Performance Manager. The tests were created with the help of Java, IBM Rational Functional Tester and an internal IBM DB2 SQL query workload tool.

skills

Agile Scrum, Kanban

Database Querying, modelling and configuring

Design Human-centered, Personas, Scenarios, Evaluations, Wireframes, Rapid proto-

typing, Lo-Fi and Hi-Fi prototypes, Questionnaires, Interviews, Contextual In-

quiry

Hardware Arduino

Object Object oriented analysis, design and programming

OS Mac OS X, Windows, Linux

Programming JavaScript(Angular, ¡Query, Processing), HTML, CSS(Bootstrap), C#, ASP.NET

MVC, WPF(MVVM), Java, Python, Ruby(on Rails), C/C++/, ABAP, Android, As-

sembler

Tools After Effects, Axure, Balsamiq, Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop

interests

Personal: I played soccer in a team for about ten years when growing up and still follow soccer in general excessively. Other than that, I like cycling, hiking, being outside and enjoying nature or reading different kinds of literature.

Professional: Over the years that I have worked, I have developed an interest for prototyping itself as well as creating and shaping user experience. This is also the main reason I moved to Sweden, to study Human-computer Interaction and Social Media.

profile

I am open minded. I have the ability to quickly adapt to changing situations. I am able to identify and troubleshoot issues. I have experience in working in multicultural teams and high performance environments. There is still a lot for me to learn, but I like to learn and I am a fast learner. I am a self-starter and try to keep up with state of the art. I consider myself as a multi-talented person, being able to get a lot of different things done.